# JinYuan Teo

Undergraduate at Singapore Management University

# Summary

I'm currently a sophomore in Singapore Management University pursing a Bachelor of Science in Information System. The development of technology and the effects it has had on civilization has always fascinated me, and generated within me a profound interest in computing and business management. My passion for technology has expanded after I decided to further my education in this field. I'm highly motivated and task oriented individual with the ability to perform and deliver results. A strong team player with the ability to motivate others, and to get the job done efficiently and effectively. I've held key appointment as president and organizing committee member for school-wide events and school clubs, with much experience in leading and managing teams comprising of members of diverse backgrounds, skills and traits.

### Education

#### **Singapore Management University**

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Information System, 2014 - 2018 Activities and Societies: SMU Challenge 2015 (Logistics)

# **Singapore Polytechnic**

Diploma in Information Technology (Information System), Information Technology, 2009 - 2012

Activities and Societies: Astronomy club

#### **Institute of Technical Education College East**

NITEC, Information Communication Technology, 2007 - 2008

Grade: 4.0

Activities and Societies: President of Audio Visual Club and Computer Club

# Experience

# Teaching Assistant at SMU - Singapore Management University

August 2015 - Present (4 months)

Teaching Assistant for IS200 - Software Foundation (Java) Assist professor in conducting in-class exercises. Conduct consultation sessions for students.

## Application Developer (Intern) at Singapore Polytechnic

2011 - 2011 (less than a year)

Conducted research on various smart home technology available on the market and the adoption rate of such system in Singapore. Collaborated with students from the engineering faculty and jointly developed and deployed smart Home Energy Management System comprising of a mobile, web and desktop application.

## Certifications

## **Programming for Everybody (Python)**

Coursera August 2014

## Proxor Software Developer Examination(SDE) - Proxor Rating 2

Proxor May 2015

# Volunteer Experience

#### Volunteer at CHILDREN-AT-RISK EMPOWERMENT ASSOCIATION

January 2014 - Present (1 year 11 months)

Facilitated multiple tee-shirt tie-dye and silkscreen printing workshop; and conducted indoor games for children from children-at-risk empowerment association.

### Organizing Committee (Logistics) at SMU Challenge

April 2015 - Present (8 months)

SMU Challenge is a college-based social outreach project that bolsters support for members of our community. Responsibility: Consolidated and assisted in the procurement of all logistical needs of all departments and communicated with external vendor to ensure accurate and timely delivery of goods and services.

### Honors and Awards

# 3rd Place@ThinkQuest (Application Development)

Oracle

2012

EL-Green http://wayback.archive-it.org/3635/20130919154540/http://www.thinkquest.org/library/winners/2012\_application\_development.html

# 3rd Prize National Climate Change Competition - Technology Challenge

National Climate Change Secretariat

2012

#### 3rd Prize Mobile App Developer Challenge

Singapore Polytechnic

December 2011

#### SP Green Challenge. Merit Award

Singapore Polytechnic

December 2011

#### **Student Commendation Award (Individual)**

ITE College East

September 2007

#### **Student Commendation Award (Team)**

ITE College East

March 2008

## **Student Commendation Award (Team)**

ITE College East

July 2008

#### **ITE CCA Medal**

May 2009

For outstanding contribution in Audio-Visual Club

## **Outstanding Graduate Award**

ITE College East

February 2009

For outstanding academic performance and co-curriculum activities

# Skills & Expertise

# **Android Development**

Java

**JavaScript** 

**jQuery** 

jQuery Mobile

**SQL** 

**ASP.NET** 

**C**#

**Windows Server** 

**JSP** 

**Microsoft Office** 

**HTML** 

**VB.NET** 

**Android** 

.NET

**Microsoft SQL Server** 

**Web Development** 

**XML** 

**MySQL** 

**Web Services** 

**Web Applications** 

**Java Enterprise Edition** 

Leadership

**Teamwork** 

**Problem Solving** 

**Project Management** 

**Requirements Analysis** 

# Languages

**English** 

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

# Organizations

# **Singapore Computer Society**

January 2010 to Present

# JinYuan Teo

Undergraduate at Singapore Management University



# 2 person has recommended JinYuan

"JinYuan is a invaluable asset to the team. He is a highly motivated, and diligent individual. One who takes initiative and dedicated to the task at hand."

— JEREMY LEE, studied with JinYuan at Singapore Management University

"JinYuan was very dedicated at PMSB group project and put in his full effort to make sure we complete on time"

— Chinkita Chugh, studied with JinYuan at Singapore Management University

Contact JinYuan on LinkedIn